Stanley Ndagi

Software Engineer well versed with working in a Scrum - Agile approach of software engineering. Experienced in remote work within cross-cultural, multinational teams across industries like fintech, agriculture and education.

Nairobi, Kenya +254 718 154 504 ndagis@gmail.com LinkedIn www.stanmd.tk

EXPERIENCE

I pride myself in writing, I write considerably having been a technical writer in various developer-centric publications. Much recently, I have taken up technical copywriting.

Technical Copywriter (Remote | Contractual)

JAN 2020 - PRESENT

I support freelance writers in CircleCI's Guest Writers Program on the benefits of tooling and automation, in this case, Continuous Integration and Delivery (CI/CD). CI/CD, an agile methodology best practice, helps overcome work-day obstacles empowering technology-driven organizations to do their best work.

Software Engineer (Remote) consulting independently

NOV 2019 - PRESENT

The past few months have seen me taking up projects where I collaborate with individuals and teams alike as a consultant. I am involved in development work, team structuring, talent sourcing and technical copywriting.

My current schedule creates more time for mentoring and learning.

Andela, Nairobi Kenya

NOV 2015 - NOV 2019

Within this period, besides being a remote engineer in various teams, I wore several hats as summarised below.

Senior Software Engineer

JAN 2018 - NOV 2019

Acted in the capacity of a Product Manager for an internal tool for a period of 3 months.

Software Engineer

NOV 2015 - JAN 2018

Acted in the capacity of a Technical Team Lead for an extended period of time.

TECHNICAL WRITING

Writer and Editorial
CircleCI Guest Writers
Program
Developerish network
TechKln community
Writer
ScotchIO

Personal publications

My Devblog

Series: DIY your web presence

SKILLS

Programming:

Python: Django, Flask, Scrapy, Apache Airflow, Pytorch, Jupyter JavaScript: VueJS

Docker, Chef, K8s Postgres, MongoDB Web: CSS3, HTML5, PWA

Tools:

CI/CD: CircleCI, SemaphoreCI Cloud services: GCP, AWS

Competencies:

Core:

Backend Development Test Driven Development Remote Work Open Source

Project Management Data Engineering Machine Learning

Bellwethr, Kansas City, Missouri, US Software Engineer | Platform and Machine Learning (Remote)

MAY 2019 - NOV 2019

As a FullStack engineer, I worked on a greenfield project involving setup and maintenance of a Data Lake. I did a good deal of DevOps collaborated on Database Design and System factoring in our Machine Learning models.

FarmLogs, Ann Arbor, Michigan, US Software Engineer (Remote)

AUG 2018 - JAN 2019

As a BackEnd engineer I extended FarmLogs GraphQL API, built internal ETL tools and was involved in the launch of a new product, a process that involved significant API modification and extension.

BrightHive, Greater Chicago Area, Illinois, US Software Engineer (Remote)

MAY 2017 - JULY 2018

As part of the initial development team, I was involved in System Design for the just-formed startup. The development work involved extending Open Source projects to fit our scope and built APIs interfacing learning institutions and state departments of Education.

Enigma, New York — Data Engineer (Remote)

OCT 2016 - FEB 2017

Wrote ETL configuration files in a DSL that instructed how open data and customer data stored in a myriad of formats would be ingested.

EDUCATION

Udacity — AI programming with Python Nanodegree

JKUAT, Kenya — BSc. Information Technology

2012-2015

PROJECTS

<u>VueDjango</u> — VueJS-Django-Webpack boilerplate (OpenSource)

This boilerplate helps developers spin up a Django application that has VueJS baked in. The project has been quoted in several technical articles, even in different languages.

Last updated: July 2020

Link to the most recent and general audience resume: https://stanmd.tk/cv.pdf
This copy of my resume is fine-tuned for this position.

(continued) DevOps IoT

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

F8 hackathon finalist, 2019 My team was listed among the top 8 finalists

Andela Employee of the Year, 2016

Awardees epitomise the company's values: Excellence, Passion, Integrity and Collaboration

VOLUNTEERING/ COMMUNITY

Team Lead, Volunteer Devs Open Digerati

Hackathon Organising Lead, 2018

FishHackathon, Kenya edition

Speaker

ForLoop Abuja, Nigeria

Mentor

- Bridging The Gap, 2019
- Youth and Success Association, Kenya, 2019
- Frauenloop, a German non-Profit, 2017-2018
- KamiLimu, 2017

Coach

- DjangoGirls Nairobi, 2016

LANGUAGES

English, Swahili